<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<bugRepository><bug id="13" opendate="2012-02-17 12:05:24" fixdate="2012-02-28 14:06:30" resolution="fixed"><buginformation><summary>[COMPRESS-176] ArchiveInputStream#getNextEntry(): Problems with WinZip directories with Umlauts - ASF JIRA</summary><description>Details




Type:


 Bug
        

 

Status:

Resolved 





Priority:


  Major                     




Resolution:

                             Fixed
                    





Affects Version/s:



1.3 







                Fix Version/s:
            



1.4 






Component/s:



Archivers 






Labels:


None


 


Environment:


Windows 7


 
Description

There is a problem when handling a WinZip-created zip with Umlauts in directories.
I'm accessing a zip file created with WinZip containing a directory with an umlaut ("ä") with ArchiveInputStream. When creating the zip file the unicode-flag of winzip had been active.
The following problem occurs when accessing the entries of the zip:
the ArchiveEntry for a directory containing an umlaut is not marked as a directory and the file names for the directory and all files contained in that directory contain backslashes instead of slashes (i.e. completely different to all other files in directories with no umlaut in their path).
There is no difference when letting the ArchiveStreamFactory decide which ArchiveInputStream to create or when using the ZipArchiveInputStream constructor with the correct encoding (I've tried different encodings CP437, CP850, ISO-8859-15, but still the problem persisted).
This problem does not occur when using the very same zip file but compressed by 7zip or the built-in Windows 7 zip functionality.


AttachmentsAttachmentsOptionsSort By NameSort By DateAscendingDescendingMkZip.java28/Feb/12 10:460.6 kBStefan Bodewigtest-7zip.zip21/Feb/12 15:280.8 kBWurstbrot mit Senftest-doublevertical.zip28/Feb/12 10:460.3 kBStefan Bodewigtest-windows.zip21/Feb/12 15:280.7 kBWurstbrot mit Senftest-winzip.zip21/Feb/12 15:280.9 kBWurstbrot mit Senftestzap-winzip.zip26/Feb/12 01:340.9 kBSebbActivity



People



Assignee:





            Stefan Bodewig
        





Reporter:





            Wurstbrot mit Senf
        


 


Votes:

0
Vote for this issue



Watchers:

0
Start watching this issue



Dates



                                    Created:
                            


17/Feb/12 12:05 




                                    Updated:
                            


28/Feb/12 14:06 




                                    Resolved:
                            


28/Feb/12 14:06</description></buginformation><fixedFiles><file>source/o</file></fixedFiles></bug></bugRepository>
