<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<bugRepository><bug id="29" opendate="2015-09-24 00:00:00" fixdate="2015-09-24 00:00:00" resolution="fixed"><buginformation><summary>Handle null type id for polymorphic values that use external type id #942</summary><description>Handle null type id for polymorphic values that use external type id
#942






    
    New issue
  


 




Have a question about this project? Sign up for a free GitHub account to open an issue and contact its maintainers and the community.
  

    Sign up for GitHub


By clicking “Sign up for GitHub”, you agree to our terms of service and
  privacy statement. We’ll occasionally send you account related emails.

    Already on GitHub?
    Sign in
    to your account
  





Jump to bottom







 Closed



stormboy

  wants to merge
  1
  commit into


  FasterXML:master

from

stormboy:master

 











 Closed





    Handle null type id for polymorphic values that use external type id
  
#942


stormboy

  wants to merge
  1
  commit into


  FasterXML:master

from

stormboy:master

 

















        Uh oh!

 There was an error while loading. Please reload this page.

 
 



 Conversation












 






      
            Copy link

 
 








stormboy


      

      commented


        Sep 24, 2015







Remove exceptions thrown when polymorphic value is null.
If there is a need to force non-null value, this could be provided as an extra property in @JsonTypeInfo, or perhaps use an existing property such as JsonProperty.required.












    Sorry, something went wrong.
  




        Uh oh!

 There was an error while loading. Please reload this page.

 
 









 
All reactions


















 






 



Handle null polymorphic value


    …
 






















a9aac22





Remove exceptions thrown when polymorphic value is null.



 








cowtowncoder




        changed the title
Handle null polymorphic value
Handle null type id for polymorphic values that use external type id
Sep 24, 2015













 






      
            Copy link

 
 




Member





cowtowncoder


      

      commented


        Sep 24, 2015









What actual problem is this fixing? Could you provide a test case to show the problem you have. I am not sure, looking at the patch alone, that this is a valid change. Type Ids are typically required, unless there is defaultImpl defined. How should actual expected polymorphic type determined, if no type id is available?















 
All reactions



















    Sorry, something went wrong.
  




        Uh oh!

 There was an error while loading. Please reload this page.

 
 

 













 






      
            Copy link

 
 




Author





stormboy


      

      commented


        Sep 24, 2015









This is a case when there exists a type Id via an EXTERNAL_PROPERTY but the polymorphic value itself is null.  See http://stackoverflow.com/questions/28089484/deserialization-with-jsonsubtypes-for-no-value-missing-property-error for an example.















 
All reactions



















    Sorry, something went wrong.
  




        Uh oh!

 There was an error while loading. Please reload this page.

 
 

 













 






      
            Copy link

 
 




Member





cowtowncoder


      

      commented


        Sep 24, 2015









Hmmh ok. That's bit unusual (nulls are not typed, so there really should not be an id IMO), but I guess it could be supported.
Would it be possible to add a simple unit test, with commentary, both to verify the fix and as bit of documentation?















 
All reactions



















    Sorry, something went wrong.
  




        Uh oh!

 There was an error while loading. Please reload this page.

 
 

 









cowtowncoder




          modified the milestones:
    

  1.9.13, 
    
  2.6.3
Sep 30, 2015







cowtowncoder




            closed this
  in
    
30b5469

Sep 30, 2015














 






      
            Copy link

 
 




Member





cowtowncoder


      

      commented


        Sep 30, 2015









@stormboy Thank you for suggesting this, it makes sense. I ended up solving the issue slightly differently, so I won't be merging the patch as is, but the end result should be same. Fix will be in 2.6.3.













 👍
1
 Smurflyiaa reacted with thumbs up emoji


 
All reactions




👍
1 reaction

















    Sorry, something went wrong.
  




        Uh oh!

 There was an error while loading. Please reload this page.

 
 

 













 






      
            Copy link

 
 




Author





stormboy


      

      commented


        Sep 30, 2015









Thanks @cowtowncoder  Sorry I didn't get back with a unit test and commentary.  I had been planning to, but have been busy working on other things.















 
All reactions



















    Sorry, something went wrong.
  




        Uh oh!

 There was an error while loading. Please reload this page.

 
 

 













 






      
            Copy link

 
 




Member





cowtowncoder


      

      commented


        Sep 30, 2015









@stormboy No problem -- SO issue and your comments clarified this enough so it was not a big deal in the end. But if you do get a chance, it would be great to verify this against 2.6.3-SNAPSHOT, if you can do a local build.















 
All reactions



















    Sorry, something went wrong.
  




        Uh oh!

 There was an error while loading. Please reload this page.

 
 

 







 





Sign up for free
to join this conversation on GitHub.
    Already have an account?
    Sign in to comment












    Reviewers
  


    No reviews





    Assignees
  

    No one assigned




    Labels
  

    None yet





    Projects
  



    None yet


 



    Milestone
  


 
2.6.3









    Development
  
Successfully merging this pull request may close these issues.





        Uh oh!

 There was an error while loading. Please reload this page.

 
 

 







      2 participants
    



 

 




 


Add this suggestion to a batch that can be applied as a single commit.
This suggestion is invalid because no changes were made to the code.
Suggestions cannot be applied while the pull request is closed.
Suggestions cannot be applied while viewing a subset of changes.
Only one suggestion per line can be applied in a batch.
Add this suggestion to a batch that can be applied as a single commit.
Applying suggestions on deleted lines is not supported.
You must change the existing code in this line in order to create a valid suggestion.
Outdated suggestions cannot be applied.
This suggestion has been applied or marked resolved.
Suggestions cannot be applied from pending reviews.
Suggestions cannot be applied on multi-line comments.
Suggestions cannot be applied while the pull request is queued to merge.
Suggestion cannot be applied right now. Please check back later.</description></buginformation><fixedFiles><file>source/c</file></fixedFiles></bug></bugRepository>
