<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<bugRepository><bug id="5" opendate="2014-08-05 00:00:00" fixdate="2014-08-05 00:00:00" resolution="fixed"><buginformation><summary>Issue Report</summary><description>Mixin annotations lost when using a mixin class hierarchy with non-mixin interfaces #515New issueCopy linkNew issueCopy linkClosedClosedMixin annotations lost when using a mixin class hierarchy with non-mixin interfaces#515Copy linkMilestone2.4.2Descriptionstevebreadopened on Aug 5, 2014Issue body actionsIn summary, mixin annotations are lost when Jackson scans a parent mixin class with Json annotations followed by an interface implemented by the parent mixin class that does not have the same Json annotations.
Jackson version: 2.4.0
Detail:
I have the following class structure
public interface Contact {
    String getCity();
}

public class ContactImpl implements Contact {
    public String getCity() { ... }
}

public class ContactMixin implements Contact {
    @JsonProperty
    public String getCity() { return null; }
}

public interface Person extends Contact {}

public class PersonImpl extends ContactImpl implements Person {}

public class PersonMixin extends ContactMixin implements Person {}
and I configure a module as
// There are other getters/properties in the Impl class that do not need to be serialized and so
// I am using the Mixin to match the interface and explicitly annotate all the inherited methods
module.disable(MapperFeature.ALLOW_FINAL_FIELDS_AS_MUTATORS)
    .disable(MapperFeature.AUTO_DETECT_FIELDS)
    .disable(MapperFeature.AUTO_DETECT_GETTERS)
    .disable(MapperFeature.AUTO_DETECT_IS_GETTERS)
    .disable(MapperFeature.INFER_PROPERTY_MUTATORS);
module.setMixInAnnotation(Person.class, PersonMixin.class);
When a PersonImpl instance is serialized, city is not included.
I debugged the code and this is what happens:
In AnnotatedClass.resolveMemberMethods() the supertypes of PersonImpl are [Person.class, Contact.class, ContactImpl.class] in that order.
It starts with Person for which it finds PersonMixin and proceeds to AnnotatedClass._addMethodMixIns(). Here the parents list has [PersonMixin, ContactMixin, Contact]. When it processes ContactMixin it adds getCity() with the JsonProperty annotation. Then it processes Contact, doesn't find getCity() in methods map and so creates a new AnnotatedMethod for getCity() with the one from the interface which has no annotation which replaces the one from ContactMixin
The workaround for this issue is to explicitly add any parent mixins to the module i.e.
module.setMixInAnnotation(Contact.class, ContactMixin.class);MetadataMetadataAssigneesNo one assignedLabelsNo labelsNo labelsTypeNo typeProjectsNo projectsMilestoneRelationshipsNone yetDevelopmentNo branches or pull requestsIssue actions</description></buginformation><fixedFiles><file>source/c</file></fixedFiles></bug></bugRepository>
