<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<bugRepository><bug id="45" opendate="2016-03-12 00:00:00" fixdate="2016-03-12 00:00:00" resolution="fixed"><buginformation><summary>Fix for #1154 #1155</summary><description>Fix for #1154
#1155






    
    New issue
  


 




Have a question about this project? Sign up for a free GitHub account to open an issue and contact its maintainers and the community.
  

    Sign up for GitHub


By clicking “Sign up for GitHub”, you agree to our terms of service and
  privacy statement. We’ll occasionally send you account related emails.

    Already on GitHub?
    Sign in
    to your account
  





Jump to bottom







 Merged



cowtowncoder
  merged 2 commits into


  FasterXML:master

from

yrodiere:patch-1

 

Mar 12, 2016










 Merged





    Fix for #1154
  
#1155


cowtowncoder
  merged 2 commits into


  FasterXML:master

from

yrodiere:patch-1

 

Mar 12, 2016
















        Uh oh!

 There was an error while loading. Please reload this page.

 
 



 Conversation












 






      
            Copy link

 
 




Contributor






yrodiere


      

      commented


        Mar 8, 2016







Fix for #1154. Partially rolls back to pre-#1111 behavior.
We just make sure that the STRING shape is chosen when Shape.ANY (the default) is set on the annotation, but some other annotation attribute was also set (pattern, locale or timezone).
This way of fixing the issue has the added benefit of respecting the user config regarding the default serialization of strings dates when @jsonformat(shape = Shape.ANY) is set on a property.












    Sorry, something went wrong.
  




        Uh oh!

 There was an error while loading. Please reload this page.

 
 









 
All reactions























 






      
            Copy link

 
 




Member





cowtowncoder


      

      commented


        Mar 8, 2016









Looks pretty good, but would it be possible to have a unit test that would fail before fix, pass after? Would be great to have something to guard against regression.
I may want to change the logic a little bit, however; if shape is explicitly defined as NUMBER, textual representation should not be enabled even if Locale (etc) happen to be specified: explicit shape value should have precedence. I can make that change, or you can do it, either way is fine.
I'll also need to merge this again 2.7 branch instead of master, to get in 2.7.3.















 
All reactions



















    Sorry, something went wrong.
  




        Uh oh!

 There was an error while loading. Please reload this page.

 
 

 













 






      
            Copy link

 
 




Contributor


Author





yrodiere


      

      commented


        Mar 9, 2016









I'll add a test.
Regarding the "NUMBER" shape, from what I see it's already handled just a few lines above.















 
All reactions



















    Sorry, something went wrong.
  




        Uh oh!

 There was an error while loading. Please reload this page.

 
 

 







 yrodiere
  

        added 2 commits
        March 9, 2016 10:08
 


 






 



Test case for FasterXML#1154























c5fba8a






 

 






 



Fix for FasterXML#1154


    …
 






















16cb352





Partially roll back to pre-FasterXML#1111 behavior.
We just make sure that the STRING shape is chosen when Shape.ANY (the default) is set on the annotation, but some other annotation attribute was also set (pattern, locale or timezone).
This way of fixing the issue has the added benefit of respecting the user config regarding the default serialization of dates when @jsonformat(shape = Shape.ANY) is set on a property.



 





 
yrodiere
force-pushed
    the
        

patch-1


 branch
    from
    a6a01ee    to
    16cb352  
Compare


March 9, 2016 09:09













 






      
            Copy link

 
 




Contributor


Author





yrodiere


      

      commented


        Mar 9, 2016









Here you go. I took the opportunity to rebase in order to:

make the test case appear first (so you can easily test before/after the fix)
squash my two fix commits
















 
All reactions



















    Sorry, something went wrong.
  




        Uh oh!

 There was an error while loading. Please reload this page.

 
 

 













 






      
            Copy link

 
 




Member





cowtowncoder


      

      commented


        Mar 10, 2016









Excellent! I'll be happy to merge this fix then.
One practical thing before merging your first contribution: we need filled Contributor License Agreement (CLA), from:
https://github.com/FasterXML/jackson/blob/master/contributor-agreement.pdf
It is the only piece of process we require, and once that one-pager is received nothing more is needed for any contributions to Jackson projects.
The simplest way usually is to print it, fill &amp; sign, scan and email to info at fasterxml dot com.
Thank you once again, looking forward to merging this &amp; including in 2.7.3 patch (which should get out within about week).















 
All reactions



















    Sorry, something went wrong.
  




        Uh oh!

 There was an error while loading. Please reload this page.

 
 

 













 






      
            Copy link

 
 




Contributor


Author





yrodiere


      

      commented


        Mar 11, 2016









Done: I just sent the CLA.















 
All reactions



















    Sorry, something went wrong.
  




        Uh oh!

 There was an error while loading. Please reload this page.

 
 

 








cowtowncoder 

      added a commit
      that referenced
      this pull request

    
Mar 12, 2016









 



Merge pull request #1155 from fenrhil/patch-1


…














37034fc





Fix for #1154










cowtowncoder



        merged commit 37034fc
      into

      

FasterXML:master


Mar 12, 2016








cowtowncoder




          added this to the 
  2.7.3 milestone


      Mar 12, 2016













 






      
            Copy link

 
 




Member





cowtowncoder


      

      commented


        Mar 12, 2016









Thank you again for the contribution! This will be included in 2.7.3.















 
All reactions



















    Sorry, something went wrong.
  




        Uh oh!

 There was an error while loading. Please reload this page.

 
 

 








cowtowncoder 

      added a commit
      that referenced
      this pull request

    
Mar 12, 2016









 



Fix #1155 fix in 2.7 branch














bacb37f













 





Sign up for free
to join this conversation on GitHub.
    Already have an account?
    Sign in to comment












    Reviewers
  


    No reviews





    Assignees
  

    No one assigned




    Labels
  

    None yet





    Projects
  



    None yet


 



    Milestone
  


 
2.7.3









    Development
  
Successfully merging this pull request may close these issues.





        Uh oh!

 There was an error while loading. Please reload this page.

 
 

 







      2 participants
    



 

 




 


Add this suggestion to a batch that can be applied as a single commit.
This suggestion is invalid because no changes were made to the code.
Suggestions cannot be applied while the pull request is closed.
Suggestions cannot be applied while viewing a subset of changes.
Only one suggestion per line can be applied in a batch.
Add this suggestion to a batch that can be applied as a single commit.
Applying suggestions on deleted lines is not supported.
You must change the existing code in this line in order to create a valid suggestion.
Outdated suggestions cannot be applied.
This suggestion has been applied or marked resolved.
Suggestions cannot be applied from pending reviews.
Suggestions cannot be applied on multi-line comments.
Suggestions cannot be applied while the pull request is queued to merge.
Suggestion cannot be applied right now. Please check back later.</description></buginformation><fixedFiles><file>source/c</file></fixedFiles></bug></bugRepository>
