<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<bugRepository><bug id="25" opendate="2019-01-16 00:00:00" fixdate="2019-01-16 00:00:00" resolution="fixed"><buginformation><summary>Fix ArrayIndexOutofBoundsException found by LGTM.com #510</summary><description>Fix ArrayIndexOutofBoundsException found by LGTM.com
#510






    
    New issue
  


 




Have a question about this project? Sign up for a free GitHub account to open an issue and contact its maintainers and the community.
  

    Sign up for GitHub


By clicking “Sign up for GitHub”, you agree to our terms of service and
  privacy statement. We’ll occasionally send you account related emails.

    Already on GitHub?
    Sign in
    to your account
  





Jump to bottom







 Closed



alexet

  wants to merge
  1
  commit into


  FasterXML:master

from

alexet:fix-array-index-out-of-bounds

 











 Closed





    Fix ArrayIndexOutofBoundsException found by LGTM.com
  
#510


alexet

  wants to merge
  1
  commit into


  FasterXML:master

from

alexet:fix-array-index-out-of-bounds

 

















        Uh oh!

 There was an error while loading. Please reload this page.

 
 



 Conversation












 






      
            Copy link

 
 








alexet


      

      commented


        Jan 16, 2019

•




          edited
          
        





Loading





        Uh oh!

 There was an error while loading. Please reload this page.

 
 
 









Seen on LGTM.com here
As codes.length == maxCode so if i == maxCode an ArrayIndexOutOfBoundsException is thrown. This happens when ALLOW_UNQUOTED_FIELD_NAMES is enabled and character 256 is found as part of a field name after needing to consume more data from the reader.
A gist containing code to trigger this path can be found here. I could find any tests for this class but if there is a place to add tests I can add the example as a test.
(Full disclosure: I'm part of the company behind LGTM.com)












    Sorry, something went wrong.
  




        Uh oh!

 There was an error while loading. Please reload this page.

 
 









 
All reactions


















 






 



Fix ArrayIndexOutofBoundsException























cab53a5






 












 






      
            Copy link

 
 




Member





cowtowncoder


      

      commented


        Jan 16, 2019









First of all, thank you for reporting this.
But would it be possible to write a test that shows how this actually works? It would be great to have a regression test, to guard against this happening in future.















 
All reactions



















    Sorry, something went wrong.
  




        Uh oh!

 There was an error while loading. Please reload this page.

 
 

 









cowtowncoder




            closed this


      Jan 16, 2019








cowtowncoder




            added
      

  2.9


  labels


      Jan 16, 2019













 






      
            Copy link

 
 




Author





alexet


      

      commented


        Jan 16, 2019









The gist I posted was an example that I can make into a test but like I said, I wasn't sure where the test should go. I can't seem to find any general parsing tests.















 
All reactions



















    Sorry, something went wrong.
  




        Uh oh!

 There was an error while loading. Please reload this page.

 
 

 













 






      
            Copy link

 
 




Member





cowtowncoder


      

      commented


        Jan 16, 2019









@aeyerstaylor ah sorry, I skimmed over issue text too fast. That should be enough, I can work with it.
There are a few tests similar to this. I'll also need to patch this in 2.9 branch (then merge forward) so I might as well make these, cover both byte- and char-backed parsers.















 
All reactions



















    Sorry, something went wrong.
  




        Uh oh!

 There was an error while loading. Please reload this page.

 
 

 









cowtowncoder




          removed
  the 

  active

 label


      Jan 17, 2019






cowtowncoder 

      added a commit
      that referenced
      this pull request

    
Jan 17, 2019









 



Fix #510














ad47c20



















 






      
            Copy link

 
 




Member





cowtowncoder


      

      commented


        Jan 18, 2019









@aeyerstaylor I ended up merging this manually -- thank you very much for submitting the report, fix! And if you find other likely bugs via LGTM (I noticed there were couple of other warnings), looking forward to more reports!















 
All reactions



















    Sorry, something went wrong.
  




        Uh oh!

 There was an error while loading. Please reload this page.

 
 

 







 





Sign up for free
to join this conversation on GitHub.
    Already have an account?
    Sign in to comment












    Reviewers
  


    No reviews





    Assignees
  

    No one assigned




    Labels
  

    None yet





    Projects
  



    None yet


 



    Milestone
  

      No milestone









    Development
  
Successfully merging this pull request may close these issues.





        Uh oh!

 There was an error while loading. Please reload this page.

 
 

 







      2 participants
    



 

 




 


Add this suggestion to a batch that can be applied as a single commit.
This suggestion is invalid because no changes were made to the code.
Suggestions cannot be applied while the pull request is closed.
Suggestions cannot be applied while viewing a subset of changes.
Only one suggestion per line can be applied in a batch.
Add this suggestion to a batch that can be applied as a single commit.
Applying suggestions on deleted lines is not supported.
You must change the existing code in this line in order to create a valid suggestion.
Outdated suggestions cannot be applied.
This suggestion has been applied or marked resolved.
Suggestions cannot be applied from pending reviews.
Suggestions cannot be applied on multi-line comments.
Suggestions cannot be applied while the pull request is queued to merge.
Suggestion cannot be applied right now. Please check back later.</description></buginformation><fixedFiles><file>source/c</file></fixedFiles></bug></bugRepository>
