<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<bugRepository><bug id="49" opendate="2016-05-31 00:00:00" fixdate="2016-05-31 00:00:00" resolution="fixed"><buginformation><summary>Issue Report</summary><description>JsonIdentityInfo incorrectly serializing forward references #1255New issueCopy linkNew issueCopy linkClosedClosedJsonIdentityInfo incorrectly serializing forward references#1255Copy linkMilestone2.6.7DescriptionXfelopened on May 31, 2016Issue body actionsI wrote this small test program to demonstrate the issue:
import com.fasterxml.jackson.annotation.JsonIdentityInfo;
import com.fasterxml.jackson.annotation.JsonIdentityReference;
import com.fasterxml.jackson.annotation.ObjectIdGenerators;
import com.fasterxml.jackson.databind.ObjectMapper;

public class ObjectIdTest {

    public static class Foo {

        @JsonIdentityReference(alwaysAsId = true)
        public Bar bar1;

        @JsonIdentityReference()
        public Bar bar2;
    }

    @JsonIdentityInfo(generator = ObjectIdGenerators.IntSequenceGenerator.class)
    public static class Bar {

    }

    public static void main(String[] args) throws Exception {
        ObjectMapper mapper = new ObjectMapper();

        // create structure to serialize
        Foo mo = new Foo();
        mo.bar1 = new Bar();
        mo.bar2 = mo.bar1;

        // serialize it
        System.out.println(mapper.writeValueAsString(mo));
    }

}
When executing this test program in the latest version (2.7.4), the output will be {"bar1":1,"bar2":{"@id":2}} - the second field will be written with a new id even though both fields reference the same object. Because of this, writing forward references is essentially impossible.
The issue seems to be the fact that BeanSerializerBase will always call WritableObjectId.generateId if the referenced object has not been written in plain format yet (https://github.com/FasterXML/jackson-databind/blob/master/src/main/java/com/fasterxml/jackson/databind/ser/std/BeanSerializerBase.java#L600). This will also happen if an id has been generated before.
It might also be smarter to only generate a new id in WritableObjectId.generateId if that hasn't happened before; as that method doesn't have a javadoc I can't tell how it is supposed to work.MetadataMetadataAssigneesNo one assignedLabelsNo labelsNo labelsTypeNo typeProjectsNo projectsMilestoneRelationshipsNone yetDevelopmentNo branches or pull requestsIssue actions</description></buginformation><fixedFiles><file>source/c</file></fixedFiles></bug></bugRepository>
