<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<bugRepository><bug id="64" opendate="2017-06-27 00:00:00" fixdate="2017-06-27 00:00:00" resolution="fixed"><buginformation><summary>Issue Report</summary><description>Incorrect handling of self-closing tags noframes, style and title cause remainder of document to be html-escaped #906New issueCopy linkNew issueCopy linkClosedClosedIncorrect handling of self-closing tags noframes, style and title cause remainder of document to be html-escaped#906Copy linkLabelsbugA confirmed bug, that we should fixA confirmed bug, that we should fixMilestone1.11.1Descriptionhannibal218bcopened on Jun 27, 2017Issue body actionsGiven the input:
&lt;html&gt;
&lt;head&gt;
	&lt;style /&gt;   &lt;!-- &lt; - - this is the culprit --&gt;
&lt;/head&gt;
&lt;body&gt;
	&lt;p&gt;Whatever&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;
&lt;/html&gt;
JSoup 1.8.2 and also http://try.jsoup.org/~lJwWpjXYUSTBeBZhdEnS3Mt56g4 will produce:
    &lt;html&gt;
     &lt;head&gt; 
      &lt;style&gt;&lt;/style&gt;
     &lt;/head&gt;
     &lt;body&gt;
       &amp;lt;/head&amp;gt; &amp;lt;body&amp;gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;Whatever&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/body&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/html&amp;gt;
     &lt;/body&gt;
    &lt;/html&gt;
With &lt;title/&gt; instead of &lt;style/&gt;, the result is different but still wrong (http://try.jsoup.org/~BZ3uoMki-r904fZxUOWJgLJO7r8 ):
&lt;html&gt;
 &lt;head&gt; 
  &lt;title&gt;&lt;/title&gt;
 &lt;/head&gt;
 &lt;body&gt;
   &amp;lt;/head&amp;gt;  
  &lt;p&gt;Whatever&lt;/p&gt;  
 &lt;/body&gt;
&lt;/html&gt;
That weirdness was fixed for &lt;script&gt; with Issue #305: http://try.jsoup.org/~3Ms6TQCrrdaA_uPgxgURYYvwFAg
&lt;html&gt;
 &lt;head&gt; 
  &lt;script&gt;&lt;/script&gt; 
 &lt;/head&gt; 
 &lt;body&gt; 
  &lt;p&gt;Whatever&lt;/p&gt;  
 &lt;/body&gt;
&lt;/html&gt;
Looking at the source, it seems only the HtmlTreeBuilderState handling for &lt;noframes&gt;, &lt;style&gt; and &lt;title&gt; in the methods handleRawText and handleRcData doesn't get along with the self-closing tags.
Any other tagname I've checked (and I tried to cover all branches of that case StartTag switch) results in a good parse similar to the &lt;script&gt; case, which is what I'd expect.
Thanks for looking into this!MetadataMetadataAssigneesNo one assignedLabelsbugA confirmed bug, that we should fixA confirmed bug, that we should fixProjectsNo projectsMilestoneRelationshipsNone yetDevelopmentNo branches or pull requestsIssue actions</description></buginformation><fixedFiles><file>source/o</file></fixedFiles></bug></bugRepository>
