<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<bugRepository><bug id="75" opendate="2017-11-29 00:00:00" fixdate="2017-11-29 00:00:00" resolution="fixed"><buginformation><summary>Issue Report</summary><description>Regression - Boolean attributes not collapsed when using HTML syntax #985New issueCopy linkNew issueCopy linkClosedClosedRegression - Boolean attributes not collapsed when using HTML syntax#985Copy linkMilestone1.11.3Descriptionpvlissopened on Nov 29, 2017Issue body actionsHello,
First off, thanks for a really useful library.
So, upgrading from 1.10.2 to 1.11.2 we see that boolean attributes are no longer collapsed when using html syntax. Example test case:
    @Test
    public void test() {
        Document document = Jsoup.parse(
                "&lt;html&gt;&lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;&lt;body&gt;&lt;hr size=\"1\" noshade=\"\"&gt;&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;");
        assertEquals("&lt;html&gt;\n" +
                     " &lt;head&gt;&lt;/head&gt;\n" +
                     " &lt;body&gt;\n" +
                     "  &lt;hr size=\"1\" noshade&gt;\n" +
                     " &lt;/body&gt;\n" +
                     "&lt;/html&gt;",
                     document.outerHtml());
    }

Tracked it down to commit "Refactored Attributes to be an array pair vs LinkedHashSet " ea1fb65. The Attibutes.html(final Appendable accum, final Document.OutputSettings out) method no longer uses Attribute and fails to check the value of the attribute for an empty string(line 320).
If I may also suggest to use Attribute.shouldCollapseAttribute(String key, String val, Document.OutputSettings out) instead as a single source of truth as the boolean expression is complex enough and easy to make a mistake. Not sure if this would have an impact in performance though but I am guessing that optimizer will inline the call at some point anyways?MetadataMetadataAssigneesNo one assignedLabelsNo labelsNo labelsProjectsNo projectsMilestoneRelationshipsNone yetDevelopmentNo branches or pull requestsIssue actions</description></buginformation><fixedFiles><file>source/o</file></fixedFiles></bug></bugRepository>
