<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<bugRepository><bug id="44" opendate="2015-04-13 00:00:00" fixdate="2015-04-13 00:00:00" resolution="fixed"><buginformation><summary>Issue Report</summary><description>Unexpected elements inside table are moved to wrong location #552New issueCopy linkNew issueCopy linkClosedClosedUnexpected elements inside table are moved to wrong location#552Copy linkDescriptionpfarrelopened on Apr 13, 2015Issue body actionsThis commit e991936 introduced a bug where handling of unexpected elements inside a table element changed, resulting in the unexpected elements being pushed further up the document than before.
I have constructed a minimal repro. Before the commit in question, the unexpected p tag would continue to be positioned after the comment (with some elements being closed early etc. to support this). After the commit, the p tag and its contents are moved up more than one table level, and now appear after the comment tag.
Obviously this input HTML is very broken and bad, but it seems that the change in behaviour was unintended.
copying @jaredstehler
@Test
public void testInvalidTableContents() throws IOException {
    File in = getFile("/htmltests/table-invalid-elements.html");
    Document doc = Jsoup.parse(in, "UTF-8");
    doc.outputSettings().prettyPrint(true);
    String rendered = doc.toString();
    int endOfEmail = rendered.indexOf("Comment");
    int guarantee = rendered.indexOf("Why am I here?");
    assertTrue("Comment not found", endOfEmail &gt; -1);
    assertTrue("Search text not found", guarantee &gt; -1);
    assertTrue("Search text did not come after comment", guarantee &gt; endOfEmail);
}

Uses the following fixture:
&lt;html&gt;
    &lt;body&gt;
        &lt;table&gt;
            &lt;tr&gt;
                &lt;td&gt;
                    &lt;table&gt;
                        &lt;tr&gt;
                            &lt;!--Comment--&gt;
                            &lt;table&gt;
                                &lt;p&gt;Why am I here?&lt;/p&gt;
                        &lt;/tr&gt;
                    &lt;/table&gt;
                &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;/tr&gt;
        &lt;/table&gt;
    &lt;/body&gt;
&lt;/html&gt;
MetadataMetadataAssigneesNo one assignedLabelsNo labelsNo labelsProjectsNo projectsMilestoneNo milestoneRelationshipsNone yetDevelopmentNo branches or pull requestsIssue actions</description></buginformation><fixedFiles><file>source/o</file></fixedFiles></bug></bugRepository>
